# **MARUT PANDYA**

Chicago, IL • 312-722-0693 • mpandya6@hawk.iit.edu • https://www.linkedin.com/in/marutpandya/

#### **SUMMARY**

Passionate software engineer experienced in writing code and algorithms in various programming languages. Possesses an unbridled passion for software engineering with comprehensive knowledge of full stack development concepts and other related techniques. Unmatched abilities to identify, understand and translate program requirements into advanced technical solutions.

# **EDUCATION**

# ILLINOIS INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY, CHICAGO, IL

Expected May 2024

### **MS** in Computer Science

Relevant Courses: Deep Learning, Cloud Computing, Design & Analysis Algorithms

#### DAYANANDA SAGAR COLLEGE OF ENGINEERING, BENGALURU, INDIA

2016 - 2020

#### **B.E** in Information Science

Relevant Courses: Data Structures & Algorithms, Operating System , Database Management, Unix, Machine Learning, Computer Architecture

#### SKILLS

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES: JavaScript, Go, Python SQL, Bash, TypeScript, C++, Java FRAMEWORKS/LIBRARIES: ReactJS, EmberJS, Redux, NodeJS, Flask, Keras

TOOLS/PLATFORMS: Kubernetes, Docker, GIT, MySQL, GraphQL, Linux, MacOS, AWS

#### **EXPERIENCE**

Member of Technical Staff - 01

2020 - 2022

### Deepfence Inc.

Bengaluru,India

- Developed features in open source project threatmapper has 2000+ stars on github with 35+ contributions.
- Developed an internal tooling to extract 100+ packages and versions from generated SBOMs and implemented runtime BOM feature in UI
- Completed a project to refactor 90% of the ReactJS Components of client application.
- Directed a project to upgrade the ReactJS v15.6.1 to ReactJS v17.0.0 upgrading 80+ dependencies for client side application
- Devised and coded a graph visualisation topology for cloud infrastructure stack. it simulates network in real time across multiple cloud vendors, regions and compute instances using Graph theory based JavaScript library AntVis g6 can scale upto 2000 nodes, improved performance of topology by13x from 150 to 2000 nodes.
- Conducted 20+ proof of concepts for topology network visualisation using the Javascript library CytoscapeJS with 5 graph algorithms.

Software Engineer 2020 - 2020

### MayaData Inc. (acquired by DataCore Software)

Bengaluru, India

- Re-designed a service to automatically patch yaml for stateful workload running on kubernetes using Go
- Implemented a service to visualise a throughput, input/output metrics of Minio object storage instance running on kubernetes deploying Grafana and Prometheus in Java
- Delivered 10 company wide product demos of application and monitoring visualisation on SaaS UI
- Collaborated with the UX designers and other team members to develop user interface and user experience of SaaS product in EmberJS

Software Engineer Intern

2020 - 2020

# MayaData Inc. (acquired by DataCore Software)

Bengaluru, India

- Designed 7 grafana dashboards for application mysql, postgresql, minio, cassandra, cockroachdb by writing YAMLs and modifying JSON·
- Coded an end to end service to fetch metrics using prometheus exporter and prompl in Java
- Expedited the bug fixing and reviewed the code across the UI in EmberJS framework and Javascript by 45%

# **PROJECTS**

• NPM PACKAGE DATA SIZE CONVERTER - Coded a Javascript utility to convert the data into 3 metric points KB, MB & GB and published the package on the NPM. It has more than 150+ downloads